# **Robin Hellemans**

## Frontend Software Engineer



I have been writing enterprise software projects for almost 10 years utilizing "the big three" SPA Frameworks (React, Angular & Vue), cloud computing with GCP/AWS and backend coding using mostly Java and NodeJS.

I see myself as a Frontend Software Engineer first, Fullstack Software Engineer second in the sense that I see frontend coding as my expertise. I do have enough backend experience to write code on the other side of the curtain and write up entire web applications from the UI level all the way down to the database level.

I started as the first employee and organized the technical structure in the software team of what is now the biggest Google Cloud partner in Belgium.

Other than that, I feel like I've built up a good amount of experience to be confident enough to advise on and work with infrastructure solutions on the cloud.

#### **SKILLS**

- React, AngularJS, Angular 2+, & Vue
- Deep knowledge of JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML and CSS
- NodeJS
- Unit/E2E Testing with Jest and Testcafe
- Module bundling with Webpack, Rollup and Vite
- Data visualization with D3.js
- Java 7 & 8, Spring Framework & JEE
- Python 3, FastAPI
- Cloud computing: GCP & AWS
- Static Site Generators and Server Side Rendering
- Technical Lead
- Containerization & microservice architectures: Docker, ECS & Kubernetes
- REST API & GraphQL consumption and production
- Query languages: SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL
- Tailwind CSS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## BASF, Gent, Belgium | Fullstack Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2023 - Present

- Building several "Digital Twin" projects related to Field Trials. Visualization of the output of ML-models that predict how well a certain fungicide works based on aerial images taken by drones.
  - JavaScript & TypeScript Vue & Angular
  - D3.js

- Tailwind CSS
- Pvthon w/ FastAPI

## **Properate, Remote |** Frontend Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2022 - OCTOBER 2023

- Building a web application that monitors buildings' energy consumption by displaying data that feeds in from sensors in the buildings. This data is displayed differently depending on the use case, while we also allow users to create in-depth analyses of a set of given time series.
  - JavaScript & TypeScript React
  - D3.js

## **Cognite**, **Remote** | Frontend Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

- Part of the InField team, which builds the InField application used by workers on all kinds of oil rigs in Norway. The InField application is built on top of Cognite Data Fusion and has won the Red Dot Award for Interface Design 2020
  - JavaScript & TypeScript React
  - o Redux

## **DEFA, Oslo, Norway** | Frontend Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

- Building several interconnected web applications to visualize and interact with data regarding the process of ordering and installing electrical car charging stations either at people's homes or company terrain
  - JavaScript & TypeScript Vue
  - Netlify
  - Webpack & Rollup
  - Unit testing with Jest
- Powered up an SVG-based animation visualizing flow of current in a typical household with an electric car charging station
  - JavaScript & TypeScript- Vue
  - JavaScript animations GSAP
  - Vite

## LaterPay, Remote | Frontend Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Implemented design and functionality "On Page Purchase" Widget
  - JavaScript & TypeScript React/Redux
  - Unit/E2E testing with Jest and Testcafe
  - Webpack
- Built Self Service wizard for merchants to ease signing up with LaterPay
  - JavaScript & TypeScript React/Redux
  - Unit/E2E testing with Jest and Testcafe
  - Python (& Django)

## IxorTalk, Mechelen, Belgium | Full Stack Software Engineer

JANUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

- Headed move to AWS for microservice-oriented IOT application
  - AWS (Most notably ECS & Cloudformation)
  - Docker
- Built microservice-oriented IOT application used by the Flemish government to analyze traffic jam incidents
  - Java 8 (Spring Framework)
- Built mobile app showing speed limits and weather conditions when driving
  - JavaScript React Native
  - Java 8 (Spring Framework)
  - o AWS
- Custom development on Ixortalk's microservice software stack
  - Java 8 (Spring Framework)
  - JavaScript React/Redux
  - o AWS

## Fourcast, Brussels, Belgium | Google Cloud Platform Engineer

OCTOBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2017

- Formalized guidelines & best practices in programming for the company
- Oversaw team of programmers working on a project for BNP Paribas Fortis
  - Technical lead
  - JavaScript AngularJS
  - o Java 7
  - o GCP
- Moved Royal Belgian Football Association's data to Google Cloud
  - o Java 8
  - o GCP
- Delivered customer facing kiosk application selling travel insurance in London airports
  - JavaScript Angular 2
  - o GCP
- Implemented web application tracking courses and student enrollments for the Flemish government
  - o Java 7
  - JavaScript AngularJS
  - Unit testing with Karma
- Authored several blogs
  - o Blogpost on Docker
  - Blogpost on Google Cloud Endpoints
- Migrated application from AngularJS to Angular 2
- Conducted technical interviews with potential new employees

## RealDolmen, Brussels, Belgium | Junior Java Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2014 - OCTOBER 2015

- Followed 3 month Java graduate course
  - Java 7 & 8 (Spring Framework & JEE)
- Consulted on internal application development for tracking packages @ DHL
  - Java 7
- Explored web frameworks as new standard within DHL

- JavaScript Angular 2
- Vaadin
- Research linked resources

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Karel De Grote Hogeschool, Antwerp, Belgium | Professional Bachelor in Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2010 - AUGUST 2014

- Highly regarded as one of the best schools in Belgium for studying Computer Science
- Created timesheet web application as part of an internship for Codete, an IT company based in Krakow,
  Poland
  - AngularJS & Firebase

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Oracle Certified Professional Java 7 Programmer
- Google Certified Cloud Architect
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS | Microsoft Exam 70-480
- Professional Scrum Developer & Professional Scrum Master

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Dutch | Mother tongue
- English | Full professional working proficiency
- Norwegian | Fluent conversational level

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

#### Contributed to

- <a href="https://github.com/Robin-Hoodie/gatsby-plugin-babel-plugin-typescript-to-proptypes">https://github.com/Robin-Hoodie/gatsby-plugin-babel-plugin-typescript-to-proptypes</a> (creator)
- <a href="https://github.com/netlify/cli">https://github.com/netlify/cli</a> Netlify CLI
- https://github.com/netlifv/netlifv-lambda Nelitfy Lambda
- https://github.com/chromaui/learnstorybook.com
- https://www.brainbase.no/
- https://github.com/lxorTalk

#### PROFILE LINKS

- LinkedIn
- Github
- Stackoverflow

## **REFERENCES**

- Kwinten Van de Broeck | kwinten.broeck@cognite.com
  - o Engineering Manager @ Cognite
- Cathrine Horn Stenstadvold | cathrine.stenstadvold@cognite.com
  - o Product Manager @ Cognite
- Erik Angelsen | erik.angelsen@cognite.com
  - o Tech Lead @ Cognite
- Adam Blanchard | adamgoodie@gmail.com
  - Engineering director @ LaterPay
- Suzanne Lemeire | <u>suzanne.lemeire@mow.vlaanderen.be</u>
  - Project Manager @ Flemish Government
- Niels Buekers | niels@fourcast.io or Valon Rexhepi | valon@fourcast.io
  - o Managing Partners / Founders @ Fourcast
- Dirk Brusselaers | dirk.brusselaers@dhl.com
  - o Project Manager @ DHL